Willow Alber-Martin

Boulder, CO · (720) 525-8664 · willow.albermartin@gmail.com · walbermartin.com

I am a driven graduate with extensive experience in instruction and communication. I am proficient at managerial tasks and event planning, with additional skills in lab settings and data science.

Education

University of Colorado, Boulder, Molecular and Cellular Biology Boulder, CO Jun. 2020 - May. 2022

Bachelor of Arts, May 2022

- GPA: 3.385/4.00

New York University, Shanghai, Biology

Shanghai, China Aug. 2018 - Jan. 2020

Bachelor of Science, No degree conferred

- GPA: 3.2/4.00

Experience

Engineers Without Borders San Fransciso Professional San Francisco, CA Apr. 2022 - Present Chapter - Technology Coordinator

- Update and manage, mailing lists, Google calendar, website, fundraising platforms, conferencing platforms, communications platform, and other chapter-wide technology uses
- Manage login & password data to chapter online accounts
- Collaborate with Marketing on website content

University of Colorado, Boulder - Learning Assistant Mentor Boulder, CO Jan. 2022 - May.

- Coach new learning assistants in pedagogy techniques

- Promote application of classroom concepts to teaching diverse arrays of students
- Provide observational and auditory feedback to learning assistants on how they can improve their teaching

- Facilitate weekly group mentoring sessions

University of Colorado, Boulder - Learning Assistant Boulder, CO Jan. 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Respond to student concerns, teach co-seminars and hold office hours.
- Facilitate conversation between students in classroom and remote settings.
- Collaborate with faculty and other learning assistants to develop concise lesson material

Mentor Collective - Mentor Boulder, CO Aug. 2021 - May. 2022

- Engage one-on-one with freshmen to offer advice and suggestions on transitioning into a college setting.
- Provide resources to students who are struggling and work with them to make academic plans.

Heart 2 Heart - Child Supervisor

Shanghai, China Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2019

2022

- Organized fundraisers for families with children in need of heart surgery, and spent time with pre and post-operational children while they were in the hospital.

Restaurateur Club - President

Shanghai, China Jan. 2021 - May. 2021

Communicated with restaurant owners in Shanghai to plan visits to their businesses for the student body chapter.

YouthRoots - Intern Denver, CO Aug. 2016 - Dec. 2017

Created teaching modules for future classes and organized the annual end of year banquet.

Certifications

Trained Mentor - Mentor Collective, 2021 BLS Certified - Red Cross, 2020

Skills:

- Conversational fluency in Mandarin
- Semi-conversational in Korean
- LaTeX, HTML/CSS
- R for data science/scripting
- BLS Certified

Lab Procedures/Assays:

- SDS-PAGE
- Plaque assays
- PCR
- Restriction Digests
- Enrichment and isolation

Select Projects

- Developed a restriction enzyme simulator using Python and the *Saccharomyces* Genome Database for identifying cheap, off-the-shelf restriction enzymes that can be used for DNA fingerprinting.
- Built a low cost incubator for growing cultures.
- Compared DIY gelatin based cellular growth medium to lab grade agar.